Guide to the George Allen and Jane Fishburne Collier Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
George Allen and Jane Fishburne Collier papers
1963-2000
SC0545
Collier, George Allen, 1942-
60 Linear feet
Collection includes field notes, research files, lecture notes, articles, papers, reprints, class files, and other materials.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
info collected on villagers is restricted: no use of names
Information about Access
Access: collection is not fully processed and parts of it are not open to research use; please consult the University Archivist for assistance.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes field notes, research files, lecture notes, articles, papers, reprints, class files, and other materials.
Access Terms
Collier, George Allen, 1942-; Collier, George Allen, 1942-; Collier, Jane Fishburne.; Anthropology.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2001-191
  - Files from study of agrarian change in Chiapas prior to 1994 (Box 1)
  - Files from study of agrarian change in Chiapas prior to 1994 (Box 2)
  - News and internet reports on Chiapas and Mexico after Jan. 1, 1994 Zapatista rebellion (Box 2)
  - Scholarly reading notes, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - Scholarly reading notes, 1979-86, 1992, and undated (Box 3)
  - Teaching files from Stanford courses (Box 3)
  - class notes, Mexico (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Mexico - lecture and reading notes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Spain trip, 1984 - notes on history of Spain (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Spain - regionalism & centralism in Sp. History & politics (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Tulane - Mesoamerica & local level politics - lecture notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reading notes for 103 - Mesoamerica (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - LAS 80 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - LAS 80 notes 1984/85 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Latin American sources in libraries & museums (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ethnohistory program 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Grant proposals for G & J Collier research: Mexico and Spain (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (1 folder) re S. U. position, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Chiapas (Zapatista) rebellion, background and aftermath: reprints and manuscript drafts, by author H thru Z (Box 4)
  - Chiapas (Zapatista) rebellion, background and aftermath: reprints and manuscript drafts, by author A thru G (Box 5)
  - Internet and news articles on 1994 rebellion and aftermath (Box 5)
  - Notes re local people in a study (1 folder) (Box 5)
  - Notes (manuscript) re rebellion (1 folder) (Box 5)
  - Maps, sources, and miscellany on Chiapas (1 folder) (Box 5)
  - Internet and other media coverage of Chiapas 1994 rebellion and aftermath (still in binders) (Box 6)
  - Internet and other media coverage of Chiapas 1994 rebellion and aftermath (Box 7)
  - Research on agrarian change in Chiapas before 1994 rebellion: subject files A – R (Box 7)
  - Research on agrarian change in Chiapas before 1994 rebellion: subject files S – Z (Box 8)
  - G. Collier's field notes (Box 8)
  - File on medical study in Chiapas (published articles and GC's notes) (Box 8)
  - Maps and aerial photographs, 1964 (Box 8-8A)
  - Research on Zinacantan and other areas of highland Chiapas prior to 1993 rebellion: collaborator files – B – R (Box 9)
  - Research on Zinacantan and other areas of highland Chiapas prior to 1993 rebellion: collaborator files – V – W (Box 10)
  - Internet and other media coverage of Chiapas 1994 rebellion and aftermath (Box 10)
  - Post-1994 Chiapas and Mexican Indianist publications and ephemera (Box 10)
    - Tiempo: informa y orienta. Indigenas Urbanos., 1997 (Box 10)
    - Proceso. 4 issues: 897, 920, 924, 960, 1994-95 (Box 10)
    - La Palabra. Boletin informativo del Centro de Informacion y Analisis de Chiapas (CIACH) no.1-2, 4-7, 9-18, 20-23, Sept. 1996-Sept. 1997 (Box 10)
    - Revista del taller de coyuntura regional. CIACH. No. 4-10, June 1989-Feb.1991 (Box 10)
    - Chiapas: la guerra de los olvidados II and III – special supplement to Ssintesis: la region, el pais, el mundo.., 1994 Jan, Mar (Box 10)
    - Ambar: ecologico, internacional, cultural y grafico. No.7. Primer aniversario., Oct.-Nov.1988 (Box 10)
    - Asuntos indigenas. No.1, Jan./Feb 1994 (Box 10)
    - The Pacific. Publication of the Graduate School of Journalism at the University of California, Berkeley. V.6, no.l, Special issue Chiapas: revolution and realilty, summer 1996 (Box 10)
    - Nexos. Sociedad, ciencia, literatura. No.194, Feb.1994, with special insert Cuaderno de Nexos: La erupcion de Chiapas, no.68 (Box 10)
    - Mexico indigena. ano 4, no. 23, 2. Epoca, July-Aug.1988; ano 5, no.27, 2. Epoca, March-April 1989; No.9, nueva epoca., June 1990 (Box 10)
    - Ojarasca; revista mensual. Pro Mexico indigena. No.3/4, Dec.1991/Jan.1992; 7, April 1992; 9, June 1992; 12, Sept. 1992; 17, Feb.1993; 22, July 1993; 31/32, april-May 1994. (Box 10)
    - Cultura sur. Programa cultural de las Fronteras del Consejo Nacional para la Cultura y las Artes. Ano.1, v.1, no.2-6, 8, 9/10; ano 3, v.2, no, 11, 13; ano 4, v.4, no.25., 1989-1993 (Box 10)
    - Literatura joven de Tabasco. (inside Cultura Sur no.25) (Box 10)
    - Letras Indigenas. No.4, March-April 1994 (Box 10)
    - Hacia una nueva vererda de desarrollo? Espacion civil por la Paz (ESPAZ), 4 January 1994 (Box 10)
    - Batz’il tz’ibubil la verdad escrita; boletin informativo de la Zona Automona Tzotz Choj. Ano 1, no. 9, Sept. 1997 (Box 10)
    - Jose Ruben Orantes Garcia. La insurgencia social y el codigo etico en la antropologia. Small typescript pamphlet, no date (Box 10)
    - El despertador Mexicano. Organo informativo de EZLN Mexico. No.1, Dec.1993 (Box 10)
  - Introduction to Color by Ralph M. Evans (1948) (Box 10)
  - Backup originals of microfilmed research and scholarly materials in microfiche archives [see box 1 in original accession of Collier papers] (prior to 1974) (Box 11)
  - Post 1994 Chiapas and Mexican Indianist publications (newsprint) (Box 12)
  - Farnswell-Muisell (?) color discrimination (?) test materials (wooden box) used in 1960-63 research on Maya color language (Box 13)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-278
  - Jane Collier – Research for Marriage and Inequality book, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Jane Collier – field notes and research materials, Zinacanton, Chiapas (Box 2)
  - Jane Collier – conference papers, talks, and research proposals (Box 3)
  - Jane Collier – field notes, etc, Zinacantan, Chiapas 1960s (Box 4)
  - Jane and George Collier – field notes and other materials from Spain 1960s (Box 5)
  - Jane Collier – research materials, Zinacantan law 1990s (Box 6)
  - Jane Collier – course materials on gender (Box 7)
  - Jane Collier – Liberia research 1971; San Felipe, Chiapas, 1973; Maya kinship early 1960s (Box 8)
  - Jane Collier – course materials on law and politics (Box 9)
  - Jane Collier – research materials re indigenous rights and law, Chiapas 1990s (Box 10)
  - Jane and George Collier – research materials, Spain 1980s (Box 11)
  - Jane and George Collier – Spanish research materials and Jane's chapter drafts of Duty to Desire, 1950s (Box 12)
  - Jane and George Collier – Spanish research materials and Jane's chapter drafts of Duty to Desire, 1950s (Box 13)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-280
  - Papers, articles, reprints, 1968-87 (Box 1)
  - Papers, articles, reprints, 1987-2000 (Box 2)
  - Biographical/bibliographic files (Box 2)
  - Lecture notes (Box 2)
  - Field notes, 1996-97 (Box 2)
  - Summary of Zinacantan Actas (Box 2)
  - Copies of the Zinacantan Actas (some as photocopies, some as photographs), 1977-97 (Box 3)
  - Photographs of Zinacantan Cabildo, 1997 (Box 3)